OLMO BIANCARDI

Front End Developer

olmobiancardi.com linkedin.com/in/olmobiancardi/ (+39) 3207941786 olmo1995@gmail.com

PROFILE

An ambitious and committed Front End Developer with proven expertise to handle multiple projects, working collaboratively in international teams and delivering responsive design and user experiences while meeting challenging deadlines. Furthemore, I am experienced in digital strategy, campaign, and E-commerce project management supported by a solid knowledge of IT & programming languages.

I strongly believe that my polyvalent background allows me to think outside of the box, to create and innovate in the world of web development as well as in web marketing and digital strategy.

SKILLS

- Javascript, HTML, CSS(SASS & LESS), C, Java
- Git, Webpack, React.js,
 Bootstrap, Foundation, NPM,
 Salesforce(SFCC), Jira, Octane,
 Confluence
- InVision, Figma, Photoshop

WORK EXPERIENCE

L'Oréal, Milan(Italy) — Web Developer & E-commerce (DTC) Project Manager for the Luxury Division @ L'Oréal Italy

NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Responsible for the digital and E-commerce strategy for L'Oréal Luxe Italy. (10 million visits per year) My role was to ensure L'Oréal Brands Portfolio accelerated and expanded direct E-commerce business across Italy.

- Served as webmaster for several E-commerce D2C projects (Kiehl's, Lancôme, Biotherm, Urban Decay) implementing all platform improvements, resulting in an overall revenue increase of 37% from 2020 to 2021 YTD.
- Provided web solutions based on specific business needs for promotions, campaigns, presentations, customer service and online services.
- Managed the migration of the different websites (1,500+ products) to a new version, reducing the pages load time of 52%, collaborating with graphic designers, web developers, project managers and international business teams.

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership, Communication, Goal Oriented, Teamwork, Curiosity, Patience, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Organized, Entrepreneurial Mindset

CERTIFICATIONS

- Udacity 2020, Front End Web Developer Nanodegree
- IELTS 2019 (C1)

- Orchestrated the development of new features and design updates to ensure an excellent user experience and customer journey.
- Developed a dynamic quick add to cart feature using JavaScript, HTML and CSS, which was adopted by several other countries within L'Oréal Europe.
- Created custom web pages from themes using SalesForce Commerce Cloud (SFCC).
- Ensured an agile, bug free user experience on our D2C Ecommerce platform, following global E-commerce requirements and brands guidelines.
- Built a new E-commerce strategy for the next 2 years. Onboarded new partners whilst scaling existing retailers and third parties with a focus on price, pack and hierarchy.
- Responsible for creating the people's development vision, strategy and roadmap. Led the team on project ideation and prioritization, member's work assignment, quarterly goal setting and performance assessment, 1:1s.
- Provided internal training programs that led to an evolution and strengthening of the Digital team.
- Conducted weekly discovery and planning sessions around technical solutions and integrations for our D2C environments.
- Implemented A/B testing to continually optimise the customer journey across various assets.

Deloitte, Milan(Italy) — Front End Developer @ Deloitte Digital SEPTEMBER 2019 - JUNE 2020

Inside a team of a complex multi-brand B2C E-commerce replatforming project for some major Italian Fashion and Luxury companies.

- Collaborated closely with back end developers to build new web pages and update existing features, using JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Brought to life user interfaces created by design teams using latest web standards technologies and using SalesForce Commerce Cloud. (SFCC)
- Tackled several bug fixes regarding the user interface, such as styling of images/text, pages not loading properly or from the correct source, and browser compatibility.
- Emphasized cross-browser compatibility and performance.
- Designed and implemented HTML email templates and newsletters for marketing campaigns.
- Developed solutions with Salesforce Page Designer tool to create reusable web components.
- · Worked with Scrum methodologies, in an agile environment.

The commerce platform used during this project is Salesforce B2C Commerce Cloud.

LANGUAGES

- Italian(Native)
- English(C1)
- · Japanese(Basic)

INTERESTS

Filmmaking, Surfing, Rock climbing, Tennis, Astronomy, Technology, Video Games, Traveling, Reading

REFERENCES

- Roberta Vinciguerra Digital & E-commerce Director at L'Oréal Luxe
 roberta.vinciguerra@loreal.com
- Marco Delevati Director at Deloitte Digital

marco.delevati@deloitte.com

WORK AUTHORIZATION

• STUDENT VISA 500 (no sponsorship required)

EDUCATION

Politecnico di Milano, Milan(Italy) — Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering SEPTEMBER 2015 - MARCH 2020

PROJECTS

Portfolio Website - 2020

- Created my personal Website, a web application built with Javascript, HTML, CSS.
- Used the building tool Webpack to minify assets into a few bundles.

Rock/Paper/Scissors Game -2020

- Developed a rock/paper/scissors game using React.js.
- Designed the final product aesthetic and user experience.

Travel App -2020

- Built a complex travel application that gets information about the user's upcoming trip and dynamically populates the UI.
- Implemented Service Workers to allow offline access.

NLP Analysis Web App -2020

- Built a web tool that allows users to run Natural Language Processing (NLP) on articles or blogs found on other websites.
- Implemented a new API called MeaningCloud to calculate rolling sentiment averages on aggregated data.

Weather Journal App -2020

- Created an asynchronous web app that uses Web API and user data to dynamically update the UI.
- Set up a server environment with Node.JS and Express.